Transcript:
[music]
>> Okay, good afternoon and welcome back
everyone to our options education
webinar series. My name is Tony Zhang.
I'm the chief strategist here at
OptionsPlay.
>> [snorts]
>> And today we're going to be talking
about how to position for a
stagflationary world, strategies for a
war-torn market.
Now, certainly looking at the markets
today, you would be remissed if you
didn't think that the war was over and
that everything was going to go back to
normal.
However, I think we've all seen over the
last five or six weeks that markets have
been incredibly volatile.
We've gone from major swings from one
end to the other end of the extreme from
extreme optimism to extreme pessimism.
But the one thing that I
am walking away from what we're seeing
here in the markets right now is the
view that we are heading into a
stagflationary environment.
Um for those of you that are not
familiar, stagflation is essentially the
combination of inflation, which this
round of inflation is being driven by
higher energy prices,
higher fertilizer prices, which will
translate into higher food prices. Um
and we've already seen that before the
start of the Iran war. We saw a hotter
than expected inflation print in
February,
uh much hotter than expected inflation
print in March as a result of the war.
And my expectation is that will likely
continue.
And then you combine that with consumer
confidence reaching a record low.
This is really where
consumers are feeling quite pessimistic
about the future from an economic
perspective. We see job numbers that
continue to be incredibly, incredibly
noisy to the point where we really can't
even rely on those job numbers because
of how big the swings are from month to
month. It's really hard to gauge the
strength of the labor market from those
job numbers cuz one month you're seeing
a negative 130,000 jobs, next month
you're seeing positive 190,000 jobs. We
really haven't seen swings this large
in job numbers, uh at least in in my
investment history. I don't remember
ever seeing job numbers this noisy. Uh
it really doesn't give me a lot of
confidence in the shape of the US
economy. Now, corporate earnings so far
have been holding up quite well, so that
doesn't from my perspective, I don't
necessarily believe that we're headed
for uh a major market crash or a bear
market per se, but a stagflationary
environment is very much in the cards.
And the question is how do you position
for it?
Um but I do want to take a step back and
ensure that
you know, what we're going to learn here
today is not just going to be relevant
for
tomorrow. It's not just going to be
relevant for the for next week. It's
really going to be relevant for you
uh into the future. It you know, whether
that's stagflation today, AI tomorrow,
or whatever theme becomes the relevant
theme for investors a month from now,
three months from now, a year from now,
how do you set up your stock charts and
OptionsPlay together to always be at the
forefront of what's moving and more
importantly, how do you make sure that
you are always finding the most optimal
option strategy to trade the current
market. That's what I want to make sure
that you learn from today's session,
essentially future-proofing yourself
with regards to the
the use of OptionsPlay here at
StockCharts. So,
at the moment, the the backdrop that we
have is somewhat concerning. 10-year
yields continue to rise
and remain elevated at that 4.3% level.
At this stage, investors are not
expecting any rate cuts here for 2026.
That is a that's putting the bond market
and more specifically the private credit
market at stress. You have oil prices
that even though we see a decline here
in oil today,
it's still 35% higher than pre-war
levels. That's going to trickle down
into higher input cost all across the
board, higher gasoline that's going to
reduce the amount of consumer
discretionary spending as a result of
spending more on gas.
And lastly, you know, a stagflationary
environment, which is the worst-case
scenario. Now, hopefully we're able to
avoid
this worst-case scenario and reach
somewhat of a consensus or a
uh a deal in the Middle East that allows
oil to start flowing again because at
this stage with 20% of the world's oil
essentially being trapped in the Middle
East, uh you know, that doesn't bode
well for the global economy going
forward.
I think equity investors and even to
some degree
um energy traders are all trying to be
as optimistic as possible at this stage.
It feels like the the equity markets are
a lot more optimistic than the energy
space. If you look at kind of the price
of physical spot oil,
it's a pretty big disconnect from what
we're seeing in equities and even a
pretty big disconnect from what we're
seeing from the futures market. It
really speaks to almost panic as to how
much
um spot oil is costing buyers right now
because of how tight supply is as a
result of the Strait of Hormuz being
closed. Now, if you look at the futures
market, that really speaks to the fact
that investors are hopeful that this
gets resolved sometime in the next
couple of months. But even then, I think
that that the likelihood of that is
becoming more and more slim every day
that passes as the conflict in the
Middle East remains at a standstill
right now with regards to a resolution.
So, what I'm going to show you here
today is, like I said, relevant to
today's markets, but the steps that I'll
be showing you is
relevant or to it is is helping you
understand a process that you can apply
to any market going forward.
Uh hopefully what we're seeing here in
the Middle East is resolved sooner than
later and that we can move on to bigger
and better things such as the current AI
infrastructure
um
buildout. And and that's another quiet
rotation that we're seeing underneath
the surface that's kind of being
uh not ignored, but certainly dampened
as a result of the headlines out of the
Middle East.
But semiconductors, best-performing
sector at the moment, outperforming the
S&P 500, um
breaking out to new all-time highs in
many stocks.
I think worth taking a look at. So,
we're going to explore all of that here
today. So, the steps that I want to make
sure that you learn from today's session
is
setting up chart list from different
scans. And this is really going to help
you understand. This is going to help
you frame
your research when you're looking for
option strategies.
Then we'll show you how to optimize
option strategies on those chart list.
And then lastly, what I'll do is I want
to show you how to automate your
workflow and significantly reduce the
amount of time it takes for you to find
a top-performing option strategy in a
matter of seconds for the markets that
are moving
on any given day.
So, let's go ahead and flip over to
um the StockCharts integration.
So,
for any of you that has
uh for any of you that trade options
here today,
um
you're probably all familiar with an
options chain
that looks like something like this.
Lots and lots of numbers, calls on the
left, puts on the right. You have every
single expiration date, every single
strike price, and a lot of numbers on
each expiration date and strike price to
help you decide which strike price,
which expiration, which strategies to
choose.
Now,
the process for trading options using an
options chain
is incredibly time-consuming.
Not to mention that probably at least
50% of the time that you go to search
for an option strategy
ends up being abandoned because
maybe you couldn't find the right
expiration, maybe you couldn't find the
right strike price, maybe you did your
research on the options and then
realized options were too expensive or
not or not not expensive enough
depending on whether you're buying or
selling, or maybe there's earnings
coming up or there's not enough
liquidity or not enough open interest.
There's various reasons where you could
have done a lot of research on the
underlying stock, like the stock, and
then by the time you pull up the options
chain, you realize that there isn't a
valid options trade. So, you end up
wasting quite a bit of time going back
and forth between looking at your
charts, then looking at your options
chains,
finding a strategy, and then many times
not able to find exactly what you're
looking for, and starting from square
one all over again. So, what I want to
show you is a process that can help you
significantly streamline your workflow
um
using the power of the screening
capabilities that you have here at
StockCharts with the screening
capabilities that you have here with
OptionsPlay to essentially instantly
find only option strategies that are
tradeable and more importantly, rank
those trades based on best to worst so
that you're not searching through
hundreds of symbols, that you really
have the best performing option
strategies bubbled up to you at the very
top that you can review just the top
three or five names, and instantly know
that you're trading an opportunity in
the
uh in the theme or in the asset class or
in the signals that you're looking for,
and then more importantly, that you're
trading you know, the the best
performing option strategy across that
specific theme. So, that's what I want
to walk you through here today.
So,
for those of you that are using
StockCharts today, one of the most
powerful tools within StockCharts is the
advanced scan workbench.
And
the advanced scan workbench is
essentially a very powerful option
screener that you can screen across a
lot of different criteria for a specific
theme or trading strategy that you're
looking for.
So,
I'm going to show it to you in the
context of what the market is you know,
what's relevant to the market today, but
like I said, what I you know, what I'm
trying to do is teach you a process that
you can apply to any market to you know,
wherever the markets are 30 days from
now, whatever theme is important 30 days
from now, that you can take you can
replicate the steps that I'm showing you
here today for what matters
to you 30 days from now, 60 days from
now, a year from now, and always know
that you are you have the way to you
have a way to stay on top of the
markets. So, for now, let's focus on
let's say the energy sector. So, what
I'm going to do is I'm actually just
going to erase the screen criteria.
I'm going to build this from scratch,
and you have this scan components
builder to help you build these scans
from scratch. So, what I'm going to do
is I'm going to say right now, if you
look at kind of the stagflationary
environment, the primary driver of this
is going to be energy. So, what I'm
going to say is show me all stocks that
are in the energy sector and we'll keep
this really broad, and we'll say
anything with a market cap over $10
billion. So, what this does is it shows
me all stocks that are in the energy
sector that has a market cap of at least
$10 billion, and I'm just going to run
this. A really simple scan that I'm
going to run here. As you can see, this
gives me 59 different stocks of energy
stocks that have at least $10 billion in
energy
in market cap. So, this is a pretty
comprehensive
list of stocks
that are considered in the energy space,
everything from kind of your biggest
companies here like
ConocoPhillips
or Chevron, those types of companies
all the way down to something much
smaller
like DT Midstream, some of the pipeline
operators here, Cheniere Energy, the
pipeline operators. These are much
smaller entities in the energy space.
But, they all fall into the energy
sector. So, what I want to do is I want
to show you how you can screen for
opportunities in the energy sector,
which is obviously fairly broad, and
instead of having to look through 59
different stocks,
I can show you just a handful of stocks
that you really want to do a little bit
more research on, and know that you can
find the best trading opportunities in
the energy space here today. And that's
really where we're going to turn to our
our OptionsPlay
tool. But, before I do that,
any scan that you run, what you can do
is you can save a scan to a chart list.
Now, you can I I usually will name this
a specific chart list that I can
remember.
The other thing that you can actually do
here is once you've created a scan, you
can actually schedule that scan so that
it runs it on a regular basis, and what
that allows you to do is you can
essentially save a scan. So, let's say
I'm going to save this as the energy
sector
greater than let's say $10 billion.
Um and save the scan, and what I can do
is I can have this run once a day and
update a specific chart list so that I
can look at a I essentially have a list
that's updated every single day of
energy sector stocks that have at least
$10 billion in market cap. Now, you can
also do things in addition to that. You
can add technical indicators to it. You
can find you know,
a specific technical indicator. So, for
example, if like let's say you like to
use MACD or you like to use RSI or a
specific technical indicator, you can do
this and actually screen further these
types of stocks to say, "Okay, what if I
use the CCI?
Let's say at least it's it's at least
over 75, something with positive
momentum." I can run the scan, and now
as you can see, those
those stocks get narrowed down to a much
smaller list, right? So, there's a lot
of things that you can do with this
screening workbench, but let's start
let's keep things really broad here, and
let's just look at um
all
sector stocks that have at least $10
billion, and I just saved that to a
chart list. Now, before we look at
OptionsPlay and how to utilize this,
I'm let's just create a few more lists
while we're at it, right? Just so that
you get a sense for how to utilize this.
So, now let's say let's let's scrap this
here for a second. Let's let's now look
at kind of broad market indices, right?
So, let's say we wanted to take a look
at um
ETFs
ETFs that are
kind of broad-based.
So, what I wanted to actually show you
is
there are actually
sample scans that you can use. So, these
are predefined scans that you can use.
This is another way that you can screen
for opportunities here.
So, for example, if let's say you want
to use the golden cross scan, you can
run the scan here, and it'll show you
all the stocks that have reached that
have generated a golden cross here for
today. Or stocks that have crossed below
the 200-day moving average, you can see
all the stocks that have generated that,
and you can save this as a scan, and
essentially what it would it do is once
you save it as a chart list, if you
schedule it, every single day this chart
list will get automatically updated with
all the stocks that have fell below the
200-day moving average. It's an
incredibly powerful tool because it
really allows you to customize
how you see the world, how you see the
markets, and have a list that
essentially is updated every single day
for you based on
what's moved. This way, you don't have
to go searching for it. The work has
already been done for you, and you can
now
find the most optimal option strategy on
that list securities. And so, that's
what I want to show you here today,
which is the OptionsPlay Strategy
Center.
The OptionsPlay Strategy Center is an
incredibly powerful tool because like I
said, when you're trading options, a lot
of times what you do is you pull up a
chart, you look at some fundamentals,
maybe you really like the stock that
you're looking at, and then you go pull
up the options chain to try to go look
for an option strategy for that specific
stock.
And you know, at least half the time,
you're going to find something on that
options chain that's going to say, "No,
this doesn't quite work for me.
I I don't think this makes sense. I'm
going to move on to the next stock."
And you end up square starting from
square one.
The biggest time waster for me is the
amount of time it takes for me to
research an underlying security, then
find that I can't structure the right
options trade that I want. Maybe I want
to sell a put, and there's not enough
premium for it. I want to buy a call
option, and the cost
and the call options are too expensive.
There are so many reasons that, you
know, by the time you look at an options
trade, you end up abandoning that
specific idea and have to start from
square one. So, what I want to show you
is how you can remove that
from your entire workflow
for options. So, what I'm going to do is
I'm going to pull up that energy watch
list that I just showed you here. And as
you can see, in the OptionsPlay Strategy
Center, you can run the OptionsPlay
Strategy Center across any of our
pre-built scans. We have six pre-built
scans for you, three bullish, three
bearish. We have a trend following scan,
a counter trend scan, and a out-perform
and under-perform scan. These are
essentially pre-built scans that we have
built for you to help you identify
stocks that are on the move for today.
Um
but what we're going to look at here for
today is the research list that I just
showed you. Um so let's go back to our
energy
watch list. So this is our energy sector
with $10 billion or or greater. And
um or I I think I'm this might have been
a different one that I screened for that
because as you can see there's only 19
names here. So I think this was one that
had a higher um this was probably more
than $10 billion. This is probably
something in the $25 billion range as
you can see. These are 19 stocks of the
energy sector that have at least I think
$25 billion. It doesn't really matter
what
the scan is, right? However you look at
the world, you can set up the scans that
you like. And now what we're doing is
instead of looking through 19 different
charts and looking at 19 different
companies to see which one you like,
what we're going to do is we're going to
first pre- qualify everything from an
options trading perspective, right? So
regardless of what option strategies you
prefer, if you're a beginner and you're
like and you want to buy a call option,
you can select a simple strategy like a
call option. Maybe you're someone who
has a little bit more experience. Maybe
you're buying bull call spreads. Maybe
you're selling bull put spreads. Or
maybe you want to trade iron condors. We
offer it all. So let's start with
something like buying a bull call spread
for example, right? And for any strategy
we will always have defaults pre-built
for you. So that even if you don't
really know
exactly what you're looking for, you can
always go with the defaults as a
starting point and have the research be
presented to you. So what I've done here
is I'm said I'm bullish on the energy
sector. I like buying bull call spreads.
Show me strategies across these 19
stocks in real time. So what we're doing
here is we're basically taking these 19
stocks. We're running a 60-day balanced
bull call spread on the stocks in this
particular uh list of securities. And
what we're doing is we're ranking this
from top to bottom.
Because it doesn't make sense to look
through all 19 stocks if the options are
vastly different from one strategy to
the next. For example, if you look at
the top performing bull call spread in
the Chevron case for example, you are
risking $2,115
to potentially make $5,385.
That's a pretty decent risk-reward
ratio. That's for every uh $0.4 that you
are risking, you can potentially make $1
in rewards. Now let's scroll down to the
worst performing one here. As you can
see for Targa Resources, you can risk
$1,475
to only make $2,525.
So
while Chevron and Targa are both in the
energy sector and potentially equally
valid as a um as a long energy trade,
from an options trading perspective,
these two trades could not be further
from from each other. From a risk-reward
perspective, Chevron is head and
shoulders better than if you were to do
a trade on let's say Targa Resources or
maybe Baker Hughes. If you look at Baker
Hughes for $2,160
of risk, you can only make $3,800
worth of potential reward. So both of
these trades have almost identical risk,
right? one will generate up to $5,300 in
profit and one will only generate $3,800
worth of profit. So the idea is that do
you even want to look at Targa
Resources, Baker Hughes, Exxon Mobil and
all of these stocks and look at the
chart and look at the fundamentals and
see if it's worth looking at if you
already know that the option strategy on
the back of that is not particularly
attractive? The answer is no. You only
want to look at the trades if you
already know that there is an attractive
options trade to make, meaning a trade
that has a really strong risk-reward,
has
good liquidity. So as you can see,
Chevron is very liquid. It's got plenty
of volume. It's got plenty of open
interest here. So you've already
validated all the things that you
typically would need to look for in an
options trade before you even look at
the stock. It completely flips the
workflow from looking at the option
strategy first and then working your way
backwards to see if the stock also makes
sense.
And the idea is that because we're able
to look through all 19 option strategies
for you, we've already pre-qualified
these trades for you from an options
trading perspective so that you don't
ever have to look through 19 charts or
19 company fundamentals or 19 the news
for across 19
stocks, you really only have to look at
maybe Chevron, maybe Occidental, maybe
Devon Devon Energy, Marathon um Marathon
Petroleum because you know that these
stocks are all in this particular case
either uh very liquid, somewhat liquid
or you know, from a liquidity
perspective, you've got the liquidity
there. From a uh risk-reward
perspective, you all have very strong
risk-rewards. So that if you're looking
at that chart for Chevron and you say,
"Hey, I really like this chart. I really
like the fundamentals." You know you've
already got an options trade that you
can make on the back of it.
As opposed to the other way around, if
you were just simply looking at this
chart list, right? And and this is a
real uh example, right? Sometimes you
have you run these scans and you have
all these charts and you look at all
these charts and you and you go all this
do this research and you say, "Ah, you
know what? I really like this
ConocoPhillips
uh chart. I like the chart set up here."
You maybe look at the fundamentals. You
then you look at the options chain.
Maybe you do all of that work and then
you realize that ConocoPhillips is maybe
all the way at the bottom from a or
right in the middle here with regards to
risk-reward. It's just not I mean it's
not a bad trade. It's just not the best
trade that you can make. This is really
what this tool allows you to ensure that
when you're looking at charts or looking
at the company fundamentals, you're only
looking at charts and companies for
trades that you can make a really
strong options trade on the back of it.
Okay? And this works for all strategies.
Doesn't matter whether you're looking at
long calls, short puts, bull put
spreads, bear put spreads, whatever
strategy that you prefer, it is
optimized for you. And on top of that,
if let's say you are uh you have a very
strong preference for selling let's say
shorter dated options. Let's say you
want to sell a 7-day, you know, far out
of the money credit spread and you only
want to risk a thousand bucks. That's
all you're willing to risk. You can
click on update
and within 2 seconds everything is is is
updated for you and you can sort it
based on what is most important to you.
So for example, if you look at selling
the 7-day out of the money credit spread
EOG Resources, for every um $300 and
$880 you are risking, you can
potentially make $320,
right? Versus if you look at something
down here like Occidental, for every
$935
you're risking, you can only make $165.
So your risk-reward on this on the worst
performing trade is far worse than the
best performing trade. These are all
7-day out of the money credit spreads.
From a credit spreads perspective, all
of these trades are identical. But one
of these trades gives you a risk-reward
of two to 2.8 to one and the other ones
give you something as worse as 5.7 to
one. So why are you wasting your time
looking at the charts for our
Occidental, for Devon Energy, for
Schlumberger, for ConocoPhillips when
really from an options trading
perspective, the only one that really
makes sense is
Valero, Williams. And if you go down
this list, you might say Exxon Mobil at
4 and 1/2 to 1. That risk-reward ratio
is so terrible. I'm not even going to
bother looking at this chart.
And that is how you are going to save
hours and hours and hours of your time
looking for option strategies. And this
works across the board for any list of
stocks that you are interested in. So
for example,
let's say right now we're looking at
bullish stocks. Let's say you are in the
belief that the conflict in the Middle
East is behind us. You think that the uh
that the the the future is looks
incredibly bright. So let's look at all
the stocks that have generated a buy
signal here today, which are 37
different stocks. And you say, "I want
to buy call options and I want to buy
call options going out 60 days. I like
to be aggressive with my strike prices,
but I only want to risk $500." You can
click on update. And now instead of
looking at all 37 different stocks,
we're really only going to look at Next-
NextEra Energy, Target, Southern Co,
Chevron because these are the ones where
the call options are relatively
inexpensive compared to um you know, the
strategies here at the very bottom where
the call options are far more expensive,
right? This way I don't have to look
through all of these different stocks. I
only have to look at maybe NextEra
Energy. Take a look at whether I like
this chart here or not. As you can see,
this is a stock that recently broke out
to new relative highs. It's been forming
this base here around this $90. Maybe
now you think this is going to bounce
and start moving higher from here,
right? And then you look at the
fundamentals and maybe the fundamentals
agree with you, the analysts agree with
you, and now you've got everything that
you need for a trade, and you haven't
had to look through 19 different stocks,
search for option strategies,
uh hoping that you're going to find a
valid option strategy on the back of it,
and be able to to do that, right? And
this is incredibly helpful for a lot of
people who like to sell options. So, for
example, let's say you'd like to sell
puts, right?
All 37 stocks are theoretically good
candidates for selling puts, but Fastly
generates a 12% yield,
uh Sable Offshore generates a 10% yield,
uh and this is just for 30 days, right?
Imagine earning 30 a 10% of the stock's
value in 30 days. So, I I don't know
what Sable Offshore Corp is. Actually, I
know it it's a small
offshore
um
oil company based in California here.
Maybe you think this 12 and a you know,
this 12 and a half $12 support level is
an interesting opportunity to sell puts
here, right? Well, if you sold that $12
put, you're earning
10% of the stock's value in just 30
days.
Where else can you find that, right? You
know, you look this it basically looked
at selling a 30-day aggressive put
across all 37 stocks for you and showed
you where you can generate the most
yield so that you don't even have to
bother looking at Southern Co, Fastenal,
Energy, Chevron, and Consolidated
Edison. Look at Chevron, right?
It generates 2% over the next 30 days
versus Sable Offshore generates 10%. So,
you know, if you're selling puts,
this completely changes your workflow of
finding opportunities to sell puts
because you're not looking at stocks
that you can't generate much yield on.
You're only looking at stocks where you
can generate a significant amount of
yield on and focusing your attention on
figuring out which out of these top five
six stocks really you wouldn't mind
owning or that you wouldn't mind selling
puts on, looking at the looking at the
charts, looking at who has earnings
coming up. As you can see, Braze, you
know, I'm just looking across the board
because we're heading into earning
season. There's not a lot of stocks that
aren't reporting earnings, but Braze,
and I have no idea what Braze is, but
this is a stock that in the next 30 days
is not going to report earnings and
generates 7% yield, which annualizes to
123%
over the full year. But you're
generating 7%
in 30 days. You're not generating 7% per
year, you're generating 7% in 30 days.
So, this is really what
um the OptionsPlay Strategy Center
allows you to do is it merges any list
that's relevant to you, right? So, maybe
tomorrow, you know, you're going to say
to my you're going to say, "Hey,
semiconductors is really is really um
taking off here. Let me go to the
Advanced Scan Workbench. Let's look at
the semiconductor industry, right? Let's
say let's pull up all of the uh
semiconductors, right? Semiconductors,
let's add that. Um we'll remove this
existing one, and let's say
uh we want to look at all semiconductors
that have at least $20 billion in market
cap, right? Run this scan.
There are
32 semiconductor stocks that are at
least $20 billion in market cap. Let's
save this to our list. These are semis.
Conductors greater than $20 billion in
market cap. Save that to my list, and
now I can go back to my OptionsPlay
Strategy Center. I'll reload this
because I just created a news chart
list, and now today because
semiconductors are important to me,
I'm going to pull up that semiconductor
watch list.
And now I'm going to look at maybe
selling puts on this list now and update
and say, "Okay, you know, there are lots
of different semiconductor stocks, but
TSEM, Tower Semiconductor, will generate
9%
in the next 30 days, right? That's a
really attractive yield. Astera Labs,
8%. Intel, 7.2%. Intel's been on fire
lately, right? Versus if you look at
something like Qualcomm or Nvidia. Look
at Nvidia. Generates 2.93%,
right? So, maybe you are thinking to
yourself, "Well,
um you know,
Astera Labs and Analog Devices, similar
type companies, or maybe you're looking
at Lam Research and
uh Applied Materials, similar type
company,
um yet one generates 4 and 1/2% yield,
and the other one generates 6.6.6%,
right? Which one are you going to do
more research on? Which one are you
going to dive deeper on? I'm certainly
going to spend much more of my time on
the top four or five names rather than
avoid looking further into the ones down
here. And this is going to again save
you
hundreds of hours over a year's time in
finding option strategies, not to
mention
making sure that you're always trading
the top performing strategies every
single time. Because
even if you were able to uh quickly
identify which stocks, you know, in the
universe that you wanted to trade, you
couldn't possibly look through 30 short
puts manually to know that, "Okay, you
know, I've I've found the one that has
the best performing short put," right?
And maybe you eyeball it and you maybe
found the Intel one because that's just
a big name in your in your most likely
to look at it, but you don't know that
you found the top performing one. This
guarantees that you will always find the
top performing one. It doesn't mean that
you'll always like the stock. You might
say, "You know what, Tower
Semiconductor, I don't know anything
about it. I don't feel comfortable
selling puts on it. Astera Labs, that's
really expensive from a valuation
perspective. I don't really like it. But
Intel, Intel really seems like a a big
turnaround story. They really seem to
have um
starting to fire on all cylinders.
They're uh looking at the research, it
looks like some of their foundry
business is potentially taking off here.
This is a great opportunity. Let me go
and take a look at it." Now you know
that out of an entire semiconductor
industry, you are trading the top
performing strategy from a yield
perspective, and you've got the chart
and the fundamentals to back it up,
right? So, this is what has completely
revolutionized my personal workflow. You
know, we partnered with StockCharts 2
years ago to build this experience, and
we built it because I needed it as a
trader. I needed it as a strategist to
be able to use the scanning capabilities
here at StockCharts, and you know, I
have built lots and lots of different
scans. Look, these are all the different
scans that I have built using
StockCharts. And these and these are
just the ones that I have scheduled to
run on an automated basis for me every
single day. Um I don't have all of them
running, but I have a lot of them
running where every single morning or
every single day after the close,
my chart list gets automatically
updated. So, for example, if you look at
this scan that I run,
this is a scan that looks at um CCI, a
commodity channel index, and exponential
moving averages. So, every single day
what I'm looking for are stocks that
have pulled back
um but have still have strong momentum
here. Pulled back um to a sufficiently
enough where the risk reward looks
fairly attractive for the stock to make
a move higher here, right? And this is
these are kind of like strong stocks
that have pulled back here, and now I'm
looking for that opportunity for the
stock to continue moving higher here,
right? So, all of these stocks have met
kind of my
trading criteria,
but when it comes to options, now I can
go to my chart my OptionsPlay Strategy
Center. I look for my CCI, my bullish
CCI,
and and and and now I can look at the
strategies that I like. So, I like to
sell bull put spreads on those types of
strategies. I like to be pretty
aggressive. Uh let's say I only want to
risk $1,000. I click on update, and now
instead of looking through that whole
list one by one, I only really look at
the top few, right? Um because that's
really where the risk reward is
incredibly favorable. For me to sell a
credit spread, to risk 545 to make 355,
that's a risk reward that looks very
attractive from selling a credit spread.
Versus if you look at uh Southern Co,
I'm risking $810
to only make 390. That's far less
attractive. I'm not going to spend any
time researching Southern Co or
Occidental or NextEra Energy. I'm going
to focus on EOG, ConocoPhillips, and
Chevron because that's really where the
risk reward looks much more attractive,
and that's is really where I can find
some of the trades that I really like.
Um so,
that at a very high level is what I
wanted to show you here today.
Um
This OptionsPlay add-on that I just
showed you is available to you for just
$40 a month, which
honestly, I think is a huge bargain
considering the amount of time and
effort and automation it brings to you
as an options trader. If you trade
options even just one or two options
trades a month, even if you're just
selling covered calls,
$40 a month, you can cover that cost on
just your first trade.
If you sell if you have any equity
positions in your portfolio, I can show
you how you can generate at least $40 a
month in just your first month if not
multiple months of your subscription
by using this specific tool. So, let's
say you have
this let's just arguably say you have a
relatively small list of stocks that you
hold in your portfolio. What you can use
is the cover call screener on the stocks
that you list that you have in your
portfolio. I would go with the default
settings. We have these set default
settings set there for you for a reason.
There's been a lot of backtesting that
goes into these specific parameters, but
you can always customize those
parameters if you'd like, but I suggest
that if you go into your
the Options Play Strategies Center,
add a list of stocks that you own in
your portfolio, stocks or ETFs, and use
the cover call screener. As you can see
here, you're generating $142,
$178, $92, $100. You know, if you add
all of that up, you're talking about a
few hundred dollars worth of income in
just 45 days, enough to potentially
offset a full year's cost of Options
Play in just your first month from
selling cover calls. And even if you're
just going to do one of these trades,
you're offsetting at least one to two
months of your Options Play subscription
cost from just your first cover call.
So, you know, my goal here is not just
to show you a tool that can
significantly reduce your your your the
time for you to find trades, and at the
same time ensure that you're trading the
top-performing trades, but more
importantly, actually show you how you
can offset the cost of this tool using
the tool itself by using a strategy such
as cover calls, which does not add
additional risk to your portfolio. It's
the only option strategy in the world
that doesn't add additional risk to your
portfolio. It actually reduces risk, it
brings an income, and that income
in almost every example that I've looked
at will generate at least one month
subscription cost for Options Play if
not multiple months. Many traders have
told me that they were able to cover
their first year subscription cost from
just their first month of selling cover
calls, and I always recommend for
traders who are testing this out or
trying this out, that should be the
first thing that you do is to just load
up your portfolio, look at selling some
cover calls, generate enough income to
offset three, four, six months of of
subscription cost using that first month
of selling cover calls. Now, you can
utilize the tool essentially for free
for the next few months, and find
great trading opportunities trading
opportunities that are the
top-performing strategies for any any
any theme, any trading strategy, any way
that you like to look at the world. So,
if tomorrow we're back to Iran war and
we're back to bearish market, you can
use this tool to screen for portfolio
hedges, for bearish trades. Um
And then if things start to resolve
themselves and AI starts taking off
again and we still to see the broader
market taking off here again, now you
can look for upside opportunities using
this tool here as well. But regardless
of what the world looks like tomorrow,
you have a tool that allows you to
screen for these opportunities and
essentially do it in a way that doesn't
that automates all of the work for you.
Um so with that, that covers what I
wanted to share with you here today. Um
I really hope that this is helpful in
giving you a better understanding of
what this tool can do.
It is, like I said, one of the
uh
the most important tools in my toolbox
as an options trader because I know that
when I'm using this tool, I am finding
the best possible opportunities in the
market. And that means a lot to me in
addition to the time savings that I get
uh from this particular tool because it
essentially pre-validates
all the things that I'm looking for,
risk reward, liquidity,
uh earnings, those types of things. You
know, before I even validated an idea, I
know which ones have already passed all
of those checks so that if I'm going to
dive any deeper into a specific stock
like Akamai, um I know that it already
has solved all my other concerns that I
may have with an option strategy.
Um with that, that covers what I wanted
to share with you here today. I really
want to thank everyone for taking the
time out here this afternoon. I hope
that this helps you better understand
what tools are available to you here at
StockCharts, what are available to you
here at Options Play, and the
combination of the tools and how
powerful it is in terms of helping you
find
the best options opportunities.
With that, thank you so much. I hope you
guys have a great trading day, and I'll
see you guys here next time. Thank you
so much.
